Kim Fulton

2/6 Craigbank Avenue, New Lynn, Auckland kimjfulton87@gmail.com 021 253 4591

Profile

I have ten years of professional experience as a writer and communicator, supported by several tertiary qualifications. I currently work as the Content and Communications Lead at Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus. I've previously worked as a journalist for daily newspapers throughout the country. I have bachelor's degrees in arts and science, a diploma in journalism, and a master's degree in creative writing.

Work Experience

Content and Communications Lead, Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus

March 2018 – Present

- Write student testimonials and graduate success stories
- Cover campus news and events
- Produce regular digital newsletters for staff, students and agents
- Manage the polytechnic's social media platforms
- Manage the campus's Covid-19 communications
- Keep the website up to date and ensure a steady flow of new content
- Develop content for print resources
- Take portrait and event photos

Journalist, NZME

May 2015 – December 2016

- Pitched original stories based on information from sources, data and OIA requests
- Carried out interviews with people with a range of perspectives
- Produced stories on a range of topics including science, education, social issues, and health
- Wrote longform features on topics including immigration and religion in schools
- Loaded stories onto websites using CMS Zen.

Journalist, The Westport News

January 2012 - March 2015

- Specialised as the court and emergency services reporter
- Also covered the environment, sport, mining, education, and council rounds
- Wrote up to five stories per day
- Filled in as chief reporter for periods of up to five weeks
- Subbed work, oversaw design and decided on story placement
- Wrote and voiced radio news bulletins for Coast FM.

Education

Master of Creative Writing, Massey University, 2017 - 2018

My thesis consisted of a creative component and a research component. This degree was awarded with distinction.

National Diploma in Journalism, Waikato Institute of Technology, 2011 This diploma covered news writing, news gathering, ethics, law, and shorthand. It included an internship at the Western Leader in Auckland and another at The Tribune in Palmerston North.

Bachelor of Arts and Sciences, Massey University, 2006 -2009 I completed this conjoint degree with majors in English and ecology.

Digital Photography Training Certificate, Nelson Marlborough Institute of Technology, 2018 This 20-week course taught the fundamentals of documentary, portrait, and landscape photography.

Certificate in Bicultural Competency, Otago Polytechnic, In progress This course covers te reo, tikanga Māori, and the Treaty of Waitangi.

Publications

My news stories have appeared on the front pages of print editions of two of the country's biggest papers: The New Zealand Herald and the Dominion Post. I have also written for more than eight regional newspapers around the country. My fiction and poetry have appeared in Landfall, The New Zealand Poetry Society Anthology, Poetry NZ, JAAM, Hue and Cry, Mimicry, Takahe, Ngā Kupu Waikato: An Anthology of Waikato Poetry, The Pangolin Review, Stasis Journal, and Blackmail Press. I've recently published my first book of poetry. You can check out my portfolio here.

Awards

- Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus | Values Ambassador Award | 2018
- New Zealand Poetry Society International Poetry Competition | Second Place | 2018
- Geometry Open Book National Poetry Competition | Judge's Selection | 2018
- Takahe Monica Taylor Poetry Prize | Shortlisted | 2018
- Cathay Pacific Travel Media Awards | Highly Commended AA New Travel Writer of the Year | 2010
- Literary Artist of the Year for Palmerston North | Student City Arts Awards | 2008

Interests

Outside of work, I love sport. I played cricket at a representative level and captained my school's first eleven team growing up. I now play for the women's premier reserve team at Suburbs New Lynn Cricket Club and help out with jobs around the club. I play soccer socially for the West Auckland Association Football Club, where I've been a member for more than 20 years.

Referees

Deepika Kumar Digital Marketing and Communications Manager Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus 021 861 844 deepika.kumar@op.ac.nz

Lee Scanlon Chief Reporter The Westport News 027 283 2408 lee@westportnews.co.nz